i'm going to show you and I'm so excited
about it
the greatest snare drum tuning trick
that I know on this planet if somebody
has a better trick
show it to me and i will use it but so
far that's the best trick
so let's start with the five points for
the snare drum tuning
so the first point is I'm going to crank
up the bottom head to death
really tabletop tight this means it's
mostly one and a half or up to two turns
and I start whether whether screws of
starting to grip so it will be like this
one
one turn I like two turns on it
basically you can count to four for half
turns one two three four 1234 1234
thank you four one two three four and
one two figure 4 forgot some yep
one two three four and opposite side one
two three four
so if you tap the head it sounds like
so it's really high pressure and if the
bottom had has attention like this you
have the best snare wire response and
you can almost do whatever you want on
the top hat so let's swap the drum
around
ok so it gets now a bit
Einstein 'ish because it sounds
complicated what I'm doing now
but it is not you just have to get used
to it so i loosen all the screws and
step two is I'm gonna bring up all the
locks one turn it kind of varies on the
screws but you just have to check it out
what with what you start one and a half
time for one turn so let's bring this to
one turn
ok here's the point where started to
grip it's one go to the opposite side
fun yet yeah
one
okay pups turn
so I just . starts and we already just
one this one this one is missing one
tutoring is to put here here is it and
one turn
so we've done everything one turn on
each luck
the drum now kind of sounds like this we
haven't done anything at all besides
keeping the resonant had tabletop tied
and making one turn on each lock on the
top head
so you're i'm going to sound like this
it's very high but we keep going
step three is now it gets a bit
complicated
you bring up the twelve o'clock screw a
whole turn then you bring up the 1
o'clocks through half of terms
and you want to bring up the
eleven-o'clock screw have returned as
well
ok so we don't care how the drum sounds
now and you always keep those three
locks up here at this level you won't
touch them anymore
so the next thing is that we're going to
do drum sounds like this
we're going to news on the opposite side
of the hoop we're going to loosen the
what is it five o'clock screw one and a
half turn
you might say but a wait how can we
loosen it one and a half turn
if we only have one turn on the screw
we have more than one turn on the screen
now because we put a lot of pressure on
this side and the hoop gets up on that
side so you have kind of more attention
on this one so take this one
one and a half turns out take the seven
o'clock screw one and a half turns out
which is mostly it's totally out the
only one turn
okay and make the six o'clock screw noce
so perhaps see there's a lot on it so
now you kind of feel here and you need
to feel wrinkles if you don't feel any
wrinkles go on the five and six o'clock
seven o'clock screw and loosen it even a
bit more so now we have the wrinkles in
here so all right here we go
the wrinkle was always something that
you don't want to have in the tom-toms
but we want to have it now in the snare
drum because our snare drum is now
sounding like this very dry and now we
still have four screws that we have not
touched yet
so the four screws on the side are
simply for your tone which means you go
up and down to match your desired note
so go around with it
ok so now we turn it down and the drum
sounds like it's totally dry
you don't have an overtone you can play
can get an even drier
it's it's like a muffled drum but it's
not actually muffled and with this
method
you still have all the high frequencies
on the drum head which is very important
for the microphone and yeah we can play
now like ac/dc stuff and then you might
take a look at your set list and you
discover all my god
the next song is a fact song so what you
do is you just turn in the three screws
down here
and there is your overtone so basically
you can completely control your overtone
just with three locks above
so let's take it out and then you can
just simply dial in your desired amount
of overtones
so no pre muffled drum heads required
I really no I never use pre Muffet it's
because those heads give me just one
sound of the drum and I just can only
use that sound but I can tune or detune
any overtones out of the skin and
everything you put on the skin killed
frequencies high frequencies
no matter to move in jail or as 0 ring
or whatever
I try to avoid this all the time because
that's my basic tuning trick and I have
full control over the whole snare drum
with this system and a fucking great
snare drum trick
yes
yeah